<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>DAMON Project Website</title>
    <link>https://damonitor.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DAMON Project Website</description>
    <image>
      <title>DAMON Project Website</title>
      <url>https://damonitor.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.131.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 06:43:33 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://damonitor.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Citations</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/citations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 06:43:33 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/citations/</guid>
      <description>This post lists research papers and news articles citing DAMON. The list is best effort collection of the papers and articles, so may not be perfect.
Taehyung Lee, Sumit Monga, Young Ik Eom, and Changwoo Min. 2025. Harnessing Page Access Frequency Distribution for Efficient Memory Tiering. ACM Trans. Comput. Syst. Just Accepted (November 2025). https://doi.org/10.1145/3777549 Introduces DAMON as a recently introduced way for doing page table based access tracking that mitigates the mointoring overhead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DAMON for Write-only or Given CPUs-only Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/write_only_cpus_only_monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 12:26:10 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/write_only_cpus_only_monitoring/</guid>
      <description>From the very early days of DAMON, there were attempts to extend it for cpus-aware monitoring and write-only monitoring.
In 2022, Xin Hao proposed extending DAMON for NUMA access statistics.
In 2022 and 2025, Pedro Demarchi Gomes proposed extending DAMON for writes-only monitoring.
Those proposals are not yet upstreamed though. We continued similar DAMON extension discussions publicly and privately, with multiple parties, though.
I was recently taking some time on these, and happy to announce the first working prototype for the extensions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>`damo report heatmap` modernization for snapshots, page level monitoring and intervals auto-tuning</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damo_heatmap_modernization_2025_06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 11:44:52 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damo_heatmap_modernization_2025_06/</guid>
      <description>TL; DR: damo report heatmap has recently advanced to support modern DAMON features including age tracking, snapshots, page level monitoring, and monitoring intervals auto-tuning. It will help users intuitively understand the monitored access patterns at a glance.
DAMON in The Past: Full Recording based Monitoring At the beginning, DAMON was providing only the access frequency of each memory region in real time. Hence heatmap visualization, which shows the access frequency of each memory area in the timeline was the first and one of the best ways to see the access pattern.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the heatmap is not showing the expected access patterns?</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/why_the_heatmap_is_not_showing_the_expected_access_patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 10:19:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/why_the_heatmap_is_not_showing_the_expected_access_patterns/</guid>
      <description>TL; DR: try --draw_range all option of damo report heatmap if it shows not what you expected. --interactive_edit option can also be helpful, like below.
Problem: Scoping of Huge Time/Space damo report heatmap outputs sometimes show no expected access pattern. It is sometimes just entirely black, or shows some access pattern but not what the user expected. This post is for explaining the reason and how you can work around.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming feature: Page level peroperties based access monitoring</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_sz_filter_passed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:10:19 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_sz_filter_passed/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re working on making DAMON to be used for page level properties based access monitoring. The idea is to let users describe specific page level properties that are interested in, and provides the size of the type of memory in each regions that DAMON found unique access pattern.
Hence, users can know how much of memory of specific access temperature is having the type. For example, you can know how much of memory that not accessed for more than 20 minutes are having how much file-backed pages of a cgroup.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>damo v2.5.7 new features: temperature filtering and formatting</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damo_2_5_7_features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 21:12:13 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damo_2_5_7_features/</guid>
      <description>damo v2.5.7 is released on 2024-11-25. Two new major features on this version are temperature-based regions filtering and formatting.
Temperature &amp;ldquo;Temperature&amp;rdquo; of each memory region represents relative access hotness of the region. It is calculated as weighted sum of size, access rate (a.k.a nr_accesses) and age of each region. By default, the weights for the three properties are 0, 100, and 100. Users can manually set it using --temperature_weights option.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A guide to DAMON tuning and results interpretation for hot pages</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_tuning_guide_for_hot_pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 17:19:32 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_tuning_guide_for_hot_pages/</guid>
      <description>The initial version of this post was initially posted to DAMON mailing list as https://lore.kernel.org/20241108232536.73843-1-sj@kernel.org
Posting it here too, for visibility and after-posting updates for any needs.
One of common issues that I received from DAMON users is that DAMON&amp;rsquo;s monitoring results show hot regions much less than expected. Specifically, the users find regions of only zero or low &amp;rsquo;nr_accesses&amp;rsquo; value from the DAMON-generated access pattern snapshots.
In some cases, it turned out the problem can be alleviated by tuning DAMON parameters or changing the way to interpret the results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auto-tuning DAMOS using `damo`</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damo_autotune_example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 13:15:24 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damo_autotune_example/</guid>
      <description>Starting from Linux v6.9, DAMON provides DAMOS quota auto-tuning. It allows users to set a target metric and value. Then, DAMOS will adjust its aggressiveness (effective quota) to achieve the target.
damo users can also use the feature using --damos_quota_goal option. But apparently the usage is not well documented. Maybe it should be documented somewhere on USAGE.md of damo, but I cannot find a good splot for now. So I&amp;rsquo;m explaining the usage in more informal way on this post.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating DAMON logo using DAMON</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_heatmap_logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 13:56:02 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_heatmap_logo/</guid>
      <description>I just made a DAMON logo using DAMON, like below.
$ git clone https://github.com/sjp38/masim &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd masim $ cat damon_pixel_2 11111111 11 11 111111 11111111 11 11 11111111 11111111 1111 11111111 11111111 11 11 11111111 11111111 1111 11111111 $ ./pixels_to_access_config.py ./damon_pixel_2 $((100*1024*1024)) 300 damon.cfg $ sudo damo record &amp;#34;./masim ./configs/stairs.cfg&amp;#34; $ sudo damo report heatmap --output damon.png The output is below:
The cropped one:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DAMON Publications and Presentations</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_publications_talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 12:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_publications_talks/</guid>
      <description>This post provides lists of publications and presentations that cover DAMON. This lists are not exhaustive and is compiled to the best of our ability, as some publications or presentations may have been made without the knowledge of the DAMON maintainers. If you find a publication or announcement that should be added to this list, please let us know at sj@kernel.org and/or damon@lists.linux.dev.
Featured Publications and Talks Academic papers For people who more familiar to academic papers, DAMON papers for Middleware&#39;19 Industry and HPDC&#39;22 are recommended to read and/or cite.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DAMON News List</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 11:27:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_news/</guid>
      <description>Below is a list of news around DAMON project.
This list is not exhaustive but just a DAMON maintainer&amp;rsquo;s collection of news. If you find a news that should be added to this list, please let us know at sj@kernel.org and/or damon@lists.linux.dev.
2025 2025-11-13: An idea for DAMON-based CXL memory management aiming both bandwidth and capacity efficiency, which motivated by recent works from Micron and SK Hynix, has shared.
2025-10-03: DAMON changes including below two have been merged into Linux 6.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DAMON-based System Optimization Guide</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_optimization_guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 10:36:11 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_optimization_guide/</guid>
      <description>This document helps you estimating the amount of benefit that you could get from DAMON-based system optimizations, and describes how you could achieve it.
Check The Signs No optimization can provide same extent of benefit to every case. Therefore you should first guess how much improvements you could get using DAMON. If some of below conditions match your situation, you could consider using DAMON.
Low IPC and High Cache Miss Ratios.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DAMON Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 10:34:06 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_evaluation/</guid>
      <description>DAMON is lightweight. It increases system memory usage by 0.39% and slows target workloads down by 1.16%.
DAMON is accurate and useful for memory management optimizations. An experimental DAMON-based operation scheme for THP, namely &amp;rsquo;ethp&amp;rsquo;, removes 76.15% of THP memory overheads while preserving 51.25% of THP speedup. Another experimental DAMON-based &amp;lsquo;proactive reclamation&amp;rsquo; implementation, namely &amp;lsquo;prcl&amp;rsquo;, reduces 93.38% of residential sets and 23.63% of system memory footprint while incurring only 1.22% runtime overhead in the best case (parsec3/freqmine).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary of DAMON Development in 2022</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_stat_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 19:35:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_stat_2022/</guid>
      <description>A summary of DAMON development in 2022 has posted: https://lore.kernel.org/damon/20221229171209.162356-1-sj@kernel.org/
2022 was a year of active and healthy DAMON development.
Seven new DAMON major features were delivered to users. Some of those were featured in articles and academic papers.
It was possible thanks to the DAMON community. The community has expanded with its own mailing list and an open bi-weekly chat series. 40 people contributed their great code to DAMON via making their 275 commits merged into the mainline.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An example of DAMON usage for profiling</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_profile_callstack_example/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 07:20:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_profile_callstack_example/</guid>
      <description>I realized I didn&amp;rsquo;t introduce a good, intuitive example use case of DAMON[0] for profiling so far, though DAMON is not for only profiling. One straightforward and realistic usage of DAMON as a profiling tool would be recording the monitoring results with callstack and visualize those by timeline together.
For example, below shows that visualization for a realistic workload, namely &amp;lsquo;fft&amp;rsquo; in SPLASH-2X benchmark suite. The upper-most graph shows how DAMON-detected working set size of the workload (y-axis) changes by time (x-axis).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tests package for DAMON is released under GPL v2</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon-tests_open_sourced/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 08:47:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon-tests_open_sourced/</guid>
      <description>DAMON contains a number of tests based on the kselftest and kunit in its patchset itself. As it is preferred to contain only tests having short runtime in kernel tree, I organized time consuming tests in a package and used it in my company only. Tests could be used as a good document and essential for contributors. For the reason, I promised I will make it open source in the last kernel summit talk (https://linuxplumbersconf.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opening a Showcase Website for DAMON</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_github_page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 06:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_github_page/</guid>
      <description>A DAMON showcase website[1] is open. There are
the official documentation of DAMON[2], the heatmap format dynamic access pattern of various realistic workloads for heap area[3], mmap()-ed area[4], and stack[5] area, the dynamic working set size distribution[6] and chronological working set size changes[7], and the latest performance test results[8]. [1] https://damonitor.github.io
[2] https://damonitor.github.io/doc/html/latest
[3] https://damonitor.github.io/test/result/visual/latest/heatmap.0.html
[4] https://damonitor.github.io/test/result/visual/latest/heatmap.1.html
[5] https://damonitor.github.io/test/result/visual/latest/heatmap.2.html
[6] https://damonitor.github.io/test/result/visual/latest/wss_sz.html
[7] https://damonitor.github.io/test/result/visual/latest/wss_time.html
[8] https://damonitor.github.io/test/result/perf/latest/html/index.html</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DAMON: Data Access Monitor</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 18:21:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon/</guid>
      <description>With increasingly data-intensive workloads and limited DRAM capacity, optimal memory management based on dynamic access patterns is becoming increasingly important. Such mechanisms are only possible if accurate and efficient dynamic access pattern monitoring is available.
DAMON is a Linux kernel subsystem for such data access monitoring and access-aware system operations. It is designed with its key access monitroing mechanisms and a major feature called DAMOS, that make it
accurate (for DRAM level memory management), light-weight (enough to be applied online in production), scalable (keeps above properties regardless of memory size) and automated (tuning and access-aware memory maangement operations).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
