<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Example on DAMON Project Website</title>
    <link>https://damonitor.github.io/tags/example/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Example on DAMON Project Website</description>
    <image>
      <title>DAMON Project Website</title>
      <url>https://damonitor.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.131.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 13:15:24 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://damonitor.github.io/tags/example/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Auto-tuning DAMOS using `damo`</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damo_autotune_example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 13:15:24 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damo_autotune_example/</guid>
      <description>Starting from Linux v6.9, DAMON provides DAMOS quota auto-tuning. It allows users to set a target metric and value. Then, DAMOS will adjust its aggressiveness (effective quota) to achieve the target.
damo users can also use the feature using --damos_quota_goal option. But apparently the usage is not well documented. Maybe it should be documented somewhere on USAGE.md of damo, but I cannot find a good splot for now. So I&amp;rsquo;m explaining the usage in more informal way on this post.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An example of DAMON usage for profiling</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_profile_callstack_example/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 07:20:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_profile_callstack_example/</guid>
      <description>I realized I didn&amp;rsquo;t introduce a good, intuitive example use case of DAMON[0] for profiling so far, though DAMON is not for only profiling. One straightforward and realistic usage of DAMON as a profiling tool would be recording the monitoring results with callstack and visualize those by timeline together.
For example, below shows that visualization for a realistic workload, namely &amp;lsquo;fft&amp;rsquo; in SPLASH-2X benchmark suite. The upper-most graph shows how DAMON-detected working set size of the workload (y-axis) changes by time (x-axis).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
