<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>projects on DAMON Project</title>
    <link>https://damonitor.github.io/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in projects on DAMON Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 11:27:07 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://damonitor.github.io/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DAMON News List</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 11:27:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_news/</guid>
      
      <description>Below is a list of news around DAMON project.
This list is not exhaustive but just a DAMON maintainer&amp;rsquo;s collection of news. If you find a news that should be added to this list, please let us know at sj@kernel.org and/or damon@lists.linux.dev.
2024 2024-10-21: Monthly PyPI downloads of DAMON user-space tool, DAMO, doubled (8,000 -&amp;gt; 16,000) again after about ten dasys. !damo_16000_monthly_downloads !damo_rolling_monthly_downloads_2024-10-21
2024-10-18: DAMON projet site started hosting its own blog.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAMON-based System Optimization Guide</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_optimization_guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 10:36:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_optimization_guide/</guid>
      
      <description>This document helps you estimating the amount of benefit that you could get from DAMON-based system optimizations, and describes how you could achieve it.
Check The Signs No optimization can provide same extent of benefit to every case. Therefore you should first guess how much improvements you could get using DAMON. If some of below conditions match your situation, you could consider using DAMON.
Low IPC and High Cache Miss Ratios.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAMON: Data Access Monitor</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 18:21:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon/</guid>
      
      <description>With increasingly data-intensive workloads and limited DRAM capacity, optimal memory management based on dynamic access patterns is becoming increasingly important. Such mechanisms are only possible if accurate and efficient dynamic access pattern monitoring is available.
DAMON is a Data Access MONitoring framework subsystem for the Linux kernel developed for such memory management. It is designed with some key mechanism (refer to Design for the detail) that make it
accurate (the monitoring output is useful enough for DRAM level memory management; It might not be appropriate for CPU Cache levels, though), light-weight (the monitoring overhead is low enough to be applied online), and scalable (the upper-bound of the overhead is in constant range regardless of the size of target workloads).</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
