<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on DAMON Project Website</title>
    <link>https://damonitor.github.io/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on DAMON Project Website</description>
    <image>
      <title>DAMON Project Website</title>
      <url>https://damonitor.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.131.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 10:36:05 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://damonitor.github.io/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DAMON News List</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 11:27:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_news/</guid>
      <description>Below is a list of news around DAMON project.
This list is not exhaustive but just a DAMON maintainer&amp;rsquo;s collection of news. If you find a news that should be added to this list, please let us know at sj@kernel.org and/or damon@lists.linux.dev.
2025 2025-11-13: An idea for DAMON-based CXL memory management aiming both bandwidth and capacity efficiency, which motivated by recent works from Micron and SK Hynix, has shared.
2025-10-03: DAMON changes including below two have been merged into Linux 6.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DAMON-based System Optimization Guide</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_optimization_guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 10:36:11 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_optimization_guide/</guid>
      <description>This document helps you estimating the amount of benefit that you could get from DAMON-based system optimizations, and describes how you could achieve it.
Check The Signs No optimization can provide same extent of benefit to every case. Therefore you should first guess how much improvements you could get using DAMON. If some of below conditions match your situation, you could consider using DAMON.
Low IPC and High Cache Miss Ratios.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DAMON: Data Access Monitor</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 18:21:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon/</guid>
      <description>With increasingly data-intensive workloads and limited DRAM capacity, optimal memory management based on dynamic access patterns is becoming increasingly important. Such mechanisms are only possible if accurate and efficient dynamic access pattern monitoring is available.
DAMON is a Linux kernel subsystem for such data access monitoring and access-aware system operations. It is designed with its key access monitroing mechanisms and a major feature called DAMOS, that make it
accurate (for DRAM level memory management), light-weight (enough to be applied online in production), scalable (keeps above properties regardless of memory size) and automated (tuning and access-aware memory maangement operations).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
