<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Features on DAMON Project Website</title>
    <link>https://damonitor.github.io/tags/features/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Features on DAMON Project Website</description>
    <image>
      <title>DAMON Project Website</title>
      <url>https://damonitor.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.131.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 11:44:52 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://damonitor.github.io/tags/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>`damo report heatmap` modernization for snapshots, page level monitoring and intervals auto-tuning</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damo_heatmap_modernization_2025_06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 11:44:52 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damo_heatmap_modernization_2025_06/</guid>
      <description>TL; DR: damo report heatmap has recently advanced to support modern DAMON features including age tracking, snapshots, page level monitoring, and monitoring intervals auto-tuning. It will help users intuitively understand the monitored access patterns at a glance.
DAMON in The Past: Full Recording based Monitoring At the beginning, DAMON was providing only the access frequency of each memory region in real time. Hence heatmap visualization, which shows the access frequency of each memory area in the timeline was the first and one of the best ways to see the access pattern.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming feature: Page level peroperties based access monitoring</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_sz_filter_passed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:10:19 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damon_sz_filter_passed/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re working on making DAMON to be used for page level properties based access monitoring. The idea is to let users describe specific page level properties that are interested in, and provides the size of the type of memory in each regions that DAMON found unique access pattern.
Hence, users can know how much of memory of specific access temperature is having the type. For example, you can know how much of memory that not accessed for more than 20 minutes are having how much file-backed pages of a cgroup.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>damo v2.5.7 new features: temperature filtering and formatting</title>
      <link>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damo_2_5_7_features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 21:12:13 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://damonitor.github.io/posts/damo_2_5_7_features/</guid>
      <description>damo v2.5.7 is released on 2024-11-25. Two new major features on this version are temperature-based regions filtering and formatting.
Temperature &amp;ldquo;Temperature&amp;rdquo; of each memory region represents relative access hotness of the region. It is calculated as weighted sum of size, access rate (a.k.a nr_accesses) and age of each region. By default, the weights for the three properties are 0, 100, and 100. Users can manually set it using --temperature_weights option.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
